Chapter 6
in Tepic she gave me the address of her friend
Tenebrosa Tenebra C's who set up
theater sets Benjamin and I
took a taxi and arrived at Avenida
de la Cripta Oscuro 11 the place
was quite gloomy it's even gloomier and
Ximo I'm just telling you that it was the neighborhood
where the cemetery is located
when we got to the cemetery gate the
taxi driver turned left then said
this is the place but are you sure you
want to get off here he pointed to a
very gloomy building in front of the building a
hearse was parked perplexed
I checked the address if it was right there
I rang the bell and a thin guy opened the door
all dressed in black
with a top hat on his head and
thick white sideburns he greeted us
in a gloomy tone good morning everyone I'm
in Tierra Mouse Tened Brax do you want to hold
a funeral can I propose
some splendid yellow coffins
decorated with cheese holes covered
in silk the color of cured cheese  with
luxurious bronze decorations in the shape
of a cat's head
the special offer I rushed to
answer him really we just wanted to
speak with a gloomy gloom cge
he muttered disappointedly and then you
are not clients of pity although it is only a
matter of time
I shuddered to do you want to speak to my
daughter now I call her he said he spoke through an
intercom
a gloomy female voice whispered what do you want
for puig and some
friends have come to see you we entered a corridor
but he stopped us no no
no that way you go to the funeral chapel I jumped back for a thousand cheese balls I am a very impressionable guy he explained I will accompany you myself but I have a client waiting for me although he is very patient the good thing about our clients is that they never complain he
opened the door and pointed to a
path that crossed the cemetery when we
were already halfway there he said
anyway thought about those
yellow coffins they are comfortable and
moss and above all they are on sale
chapter 7
we hurried along the gloomy path
of the cemetery a very fine
mist enveloping the trees and giving
the cemetery a spectral and
disturbing atmosphere we surrounded stone tombs and
marble headstones suddenly Benjamin
tugged at my jacket sleeve look
there Uncle Jerome that tomb is
rising I looked in the direction
Benjamin had pointed and a shiver ran down my spine
the marble headstone covering
a grave was
slowly rising I heard organ music
pavan
little com
the music got louder and louder
making me shiver from my tail to the
tips of my whiskers I grabbed Benjamin
by the leg and turned around to run away
but in the fog it was difficult to find our way around
and I realized we were lost
the tomb opened completely and the
organ music increased in volume
until it was deafening they were paying us
Dad
suddenly a mouse-like snout poked out of the
open grave I jumped back
shrieking terrified help
a high pitched voice screamed at mice it's
cold out here get
inside before they  you catch a
cold she was pink's friend and
spooky had brax
chapter 8
as we descended the steps
as we descended the
granite steps i looked closer at spooky she had
shiny fur inky black hair
parted in the
middle green eyes like a cat's very
long eyelashes sharp nails
painted violet her fur
shimmered with a silver dust that
sparkled in the candlelight spooky was
wearing a violet dress with
wide sleeves that fell to the floor
at the neck she wore a strange
golden crescent shaped medallion with a
magic formula engraved on it despite the
strange wardrobe i must admit that
pinky's friend was very pretty i noticed that
spooky's room was
actually an ancient burial crypt the
floor was made of stone tombstones consumed
by time and the ceiling was vaulted
in the center of the room was a
marble sarcophagus with black satin sheets
there slept spooky the crypt  It
was lit, yes you can call it that,
by a skull-shaped oil lamp.
On the walls were
spectral paintings. I shuddered and saw the
portrait of a vampire with long, sharp
fangs. One of the walls
was lined with marble shelves
containing books bound in
antique leather. A curious collection of titles: A
catalogue of coffins, A macabre
medieval tales, A tourist guide to the
monumental cemeteries of the Trans
Gratton.
In the crypt, there was only a small window
with thick iron bars and a
moth-eaten scarlet satin curtain. There
were cobwebs everywhere and a layer of
dust was a centimetre thick. Thick,
dark candles
cast gloomy shadows against the
walls, fluttering in the wind. She
closed the door of a
black marble bathroom and exclaimed, "Do you like the
decor? It's all very old, from the
12th century. By the way, what can I do for
you, darlings?" I cleared my throat and
murmured, "Good afternoon, Miss. You
gave me your name, Inc. and T&C. My name is
Stilton, Geronimo Stilton."  we
need to talk sweetheart speak
she said i have to write a book about
halloween costumes and she
pouted in the shape of a heart
benjamin tugged on my jacket and
whispered careful man spooky has a
crush on you I shuddered she
opened a black closet full of dresses
wigs and accessories and dictated to
benjamin for a quality costume you don't
wait until the last minute but rather
prepare in advance
chapter 9 spooky dictated to benjamin
the tips for halloween costumes
then she languidly murmured jerome have they never
told you that you are a very handsome little mouse
with your painted nails I scratched my
chin flirtatiously you are so fascinating I
shuddered
really currently momentarily
practically I she winked at me you
are shy
that makes you even more fascinating I love
boyfriends victim then she lit up I have
an idea Halloween night we can
organize a party at my house benjamin
was very happy or so spooky I
like the idea a halloween party how
good I wasn't that enthusiastic
but I hid it because it was true, of
course, of course, she thought about it.
We'll need a cook and a special menu.
Benjamin had an idea. Uncle, let's ask
Pink for advice. Pina is
my grandfather's housekeeper and she knows how to cook very
well. My grandfather, Torcuato, Revoltosos and
Cancer for friends are the legendary
Itemid and Ximo, founder of El Eco del
Roedor.
Chapter 10. I
picked up the phone and called Espina. Hello,
hello, I'm Ping. Who are you shouting at? She said in a high-
pitched voice:
I'm Stilton, Geronimo Stilton,
Mr. Jeronimo. She shouted: Fina. I
need your help. I have to organize
a special party. Tell me, Mr.
Jeronimo. She exclaimed:
Tell me what you need. I'm at your disposal. Say, do you know what Halloween is? I
asked her
Halloween. She was surprised. No, it's
Halloween. It's a party where
people dress up as witches, skeletons,
mummy, etc. I need a
special spooky menu. I explained to her. She
remained silent for a long time. I thought
that maybe she had been offended. Maybe
pin-up isn't your style. Maybe you'd like something
more traditional  more classic traditional
classic scream there's nothing I don't know how to
make in a modern
classic kitchen you tell me a dish that I
prepared while Tenebrosa had
given me a list of foods I
read it to her Pina she remained silent I
murmured wine you're
still there I'm here Mr.
Jerome
Pina could you cook anything of
this type on Halloween night
we will celebrate a big party at
a friend's house I'm
going right to the sewer
below the house to look for the snails
maybe I'll even find the
leeches too the
bat pellets won't be easy but this afternoon
I'll go to the cemetery in my cousin's neighborhood
I screamed worried don't you have an opinion it's a
fake joke menu in reality it's about
using normal food and yes moss I
explained to her for example the
bat pellets are dried figs the
bat eyes are olives she retorted
bellicose pretend or real it doesn't matter I'll
cook whatever she wants because I know how to
cook everything everything there's
nothing she has an opinion on I don't know how to cook
chapter 11 I
thanked Pina and hung up
Tenebrosa exclaimed purposely  Jerome
now that you have information about
costumes and a chilling menu are you
ready to start writing your book I
cleared my throat
yeah right I then almost almost yes I
said sliding towards the door she
jumped standing between the
crypt door and me oh no little darling you won't
leave without having given me at least
a kiss in return it's too easy then she
exclaimed kiss kiss kiss kiss I
shuddered then I closed my eyes and yes she
gave him a kiss I turned red what
can I do
I'm a shy
scary mouse I screamed scaring myself
Jerome you kiss like no one else you're a
real darling confess do you have a girlfriend
I blushed girlfriend actually in a
certain sense in short maybe maybe well
no not in dreams nor do I think to have the fence
she winked at Benjamin and
whispered but in a way that I could
hear her
on purpose little one then you can
tell me everything I want to know if your uncle
has any admirers who are they where they
live so I'll go take a look at
those girls  I am very jealous and also
vengeful and saying that she swirled
before my eyes her long, very long
nails painted a metallic violet
I shuddered at that moment a
bat brushed against my hours I
screamed spookily scratching my ears on
purpose this is nosferatu my
pet bat chapter 12 I looked at
my watch and was surprised it was dawn
incredible it has already become daylight
spooky she laughed it's time to go to
sleep I always go to bed at
dawn and get up at dusk
then she winked at me first
however I'll take you for a ride in
dad's new car I tried to deny the idea
of ​​riding in a hearse didn't
excite me but she insisted don't
tell me you don't trust me just because I'm a
little mouse I was
quick to deny it of course not
imagine at that moment
I understood who she reminded me of spooky well of
course she reminded me of my sister tea just like
that spooky she lifted the tombstone and
we went out to the cemetery we headed
towards the car  hearse and proudly led us in it's
the latest model it's called the
roaring bat and it has a
coffin carrier built in and even a
satellite navigation system with maps
of cemeteries around the world and he
showed me a map of the
monumental mouse cemetery and
then he let out a scream he put it in gear and
the hearse sped off
luckily at dawn the streets of ratonia
were practically deserted because
tenebrosa ran every
red light she ignored all the preferences
she took every one-way street on the
wrong side and parked on calle del
tortellini 13 in front of the echo of the
tenebrosa rodent she exclaimed "oh yeah"
see you at the halloween party you'll
dance only with me remember i'm very
jealous and she stroked my chin with her
very long nails i got out of the car
more dead than alive pale as a
requexón while she started off with a
wild giggle